<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on Farhun&#39;s Den</title>
    <link>http://localhost:60822/categories/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on Farhun&#39;s Den</description>
    <image>
      <title>Farhun&#39;s Den</title>
      <url>http://localhost:60822/images/avatar.jpg</url>
      <link>http://localhost:60822/images/avatar.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:60822/categories/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wireshark Port Filter vs Protocol Filter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60822/Wireshark-Port-Filter-vs-Protocol-Filter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:60822/Wireshark-Port-Filter-vs-Protocol-Filter/</guid>
      <description>Wireshark Port Filter vs Protocol Filter When analyzing network traffic using Wireshark, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to understand the difference between the filters to effectively isolate and examine relevant data.
We will discuss on the basis of port 80 filter and HTTP filter. Because HTTP itself uses the port 80. So, their will be some key difference when using these two filters.
Port Filter: For this filter specifically targets traffic on ports. On this case port 80, which is the standard port for HTTP communication.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AutoCad Function Key Shortcut</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60822/AutoCad-Function-Key-Shortcut/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:60822/AutoCad-Function-Key-Shortcut/</guid>
      <description>AutoCAD function key shortcuts significantly enhance efficiency by allowing users to execute common commands quickly, reducing the need for menu navigation and mouse clicks. Their streamlined access to essential functions helps CAD professionals save time and work more productively on intricate design projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Run Yacht or Portainer on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60822/How-to-Run-Yacht-or-Portainer-on-Ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:60822/How-to-Run-Yacht-or-Portainer-on-Ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Requirment needed to run Yacht or Portainer (Ubuntu) All we need to run yacht or Portainer to manage our docker container is docker itself. According to docker official documnetation we need to do the following.
First command
sudo apt-get updatesudo apt-get install ca-certificates curl gnupg This will allow apt install over HTTPS.
Second command
sudo install -m 0755 -d /etc/apt/keyringscurl -fsSL https://download.docker.com/linux/ubuntu/gpg | sudo gpg --dearmor -o /etc/apt/keyrings/docker.gpgsudo chmod a+r /etc/apt/keyrings/docker.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Git: Part Two</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60822/Basics-of-git-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:60822/Basics-of-git-2/</guid>
      <description>In the last article we learned about git stage, commit, stash, reset and remove now we will move to some other commands to give this series a proper ending for basic idea and to get starting.
Going back a commit This is essentially destroying history. So be cautious of this one.
If we want a to go back to one commit behind or we want to delete a commit - git reset --hard HEAD~1 To revert to a specfic commit - git reset commit_id - git revert commit_id Then if we want to push that to remote (origin) - git push -f origin main checking a previous commit If we want to go back and just check a commit then - git checkout commit_id We cannot work while in this checkout mode After checking that commit and want to comeback to present - git checkout master Rebase Merge and rebase works in same way but with slight variation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Git: Part One</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60822/Basics-of-git-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:60822/Basics-of-git-1/</guid>
      <description>Git in a nutshell What is git? Ans: Git is a program that constantly scans the file for changes and records them in order to create a version of those changes. That is why it is known as a version control system or version control tool. Flow of github Ans: There are different github with different flags to do many task. But here we mainly focusing on the basic git commands.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Powershell Customization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60822/powershell-customization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:60822/powershell-customization/</guid>
      <description>Powershell What exactly is PowerShell? Powershell is a task automation solution as well as a command line shell. Similar programs include bash, zsh, and others. PowerShell, on the other hand, is now cross-platform. It is now available for download on Windows, Mac, and Linux. This increases its versatility. But one thing people are afraid of is the command line. Powershell can only be run from the command line. So why not make it more appealing to use?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
